Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪Fade like drifting clouds♪
♪تتلاشى مثل السحب المنجرفة♪
♪Half dream, half illusion♪
♪نصف حلم، ونصف وهم♪
♪Fated or fleeting♪
♪مقدر أو عابر♪
♪Spring breeze falls from my brow♪
♪نسائم الربيع تهب من جبهتي♪
♪Where to go, I do not know♪
♪أين أذهب، لا أعرف♪
♪I turn, and all is gone♪
♪أتحول، وكل شيء قد ذهب♪
♪Ask how deep the dust of love runs♪
♪اسأل عن مدى عمق غبار الحب♪
♪How strong longing grows♪
♪ما أشد الشوق الذي ينمو♪
♪I play till the final note♪
♪ألعب حتى النغمة الأخيرة♪
=In The Name of Loyalty=
=باسم الولاء=
=Episode 14=
=الحلقة 14=
I know where the antidote formula
أنا أعرف أين صيغة الترياق
for the Frost Poison is.
لأن السم الصقيع هو.
It's okay now.
لا بأس الآن.
(To my brother)
(الى اخي)
(Ji,)
(من,)
(don't look for me.)
(لا تبحث عني.)
(I've endured enough suffering in the palace.)
(لقد تحملت ما يكفي من المعاناة في القصر.)
(Now I just want to be free.)
(الآن أريد فقط أن أكون حراً.)
(The position as the Empress, I no longer want it.)
(منصب الإمبراطورة، لم أعد أريده.)
My lord.
سيدي.
My lord!
سيدي!
My lord,
سيدي،
His Majesty and the waiting maid Cheng Ge...
جلالته وخادمة الانتظار تشنغ جي ...
Bring the Empress back to me. Now!
أعيدوا لي الإمبراطورة. الآن!
Yes.
نعم.
(Yunjing)
(يونجينج)
Dolls, sachets, and trinkets!
الدمى والأكياس والحلي!
Come take a look!
تعالوا وانظروا!
Lady, come take a look.
سيدتي، تعالي وألقي نظرة.
How's your poison?
كيف حال السم الخاص بك؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
It's been cured.
لقد تم شفاؤه.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
Come on.
تعال.
I'll do it myself.
سأفعل ذلك بنفسي.
There's only you and me here.
لا يوجد هنا سوى أنت وأنا.
No one else.
لا أحد آخر.
Come on.
تعال.
Now
الآن
you're poisoned by Shi Nan
لقد تم تسميمك بواسطة شي نان
and persecuted by Gao Ji.
وتعرضوا للاضطهاد من قبل غاو جي.
The road ahead
الطريق إلى الأمام
will only become more dangerous.
سوف يصبح الأمر أكثر خطورة.
Compared
مقارنة
to what my parents,
إلى ما قاله والديّ،
my brother,
أخي،
and the people of Pingxiang endured,
وتحمل شعب بينغشيانغ،
the pain I have suffered
الألم الذي عانيت منه
is nothing.
ليس شيئا.
I will tear off the hypocritical masks
سأمزق الأقنعة النفاقية
of Gao Ji and Shi Nan.
جاو جي وشي نان.
But I can't just
ولكن لا يمكنني فقط
watch as your poison...
شاهد سمك...
He's deceived me for years.
لقد خدعني لسنوات.
I'll never give in to him again.
لن أستسلم له مرة أخرى أبدًا.
Consider carefully.
فكر جيدا.
Do you truly want
هل تريد حقا
to work for the deceiver Shi Nan?
للعمل مع المخادع شي نان؟
Now Shi Nan also targets Gao Ji.
الآن يستهدف شي نان أيضًا Gao Ji.
We can use his power
يمكننا استخدام قوته
to settle our scores.
لتصفية حساباتنا.
Originally,
أصلا،
Gao Ji wanted to use Gao Zhiying
أراد Gao Ji استخدام Gao Zhiying
to have an heir for me,
أن يكون لي وريث،
and legitimize his power grab.
وإضفاء الشرعية على استيلائه على السلطة.
Now without Gao Zhiying,
الآن بدون غاو تشي ينغ،
it's our chance to counterattack.
إنها فرصتنا للهجوم المضاد.
In the imperial court,
في البلاط الإمبراطوري،
there are still loyal officials.
لا زال هناك مسؤولين مخلصين.
With Gao Ji's conduct,
مع سلوك جاو جي،
many must have harbored discontent.
لا بد أن العديد منهم كانوا يشعرون بالاستياء.
They just dare not speak out.
إنهم لا يجرؤون على التحدث.
You mean...
هل تقصد...
Now,
الآن،
my Gu poison is cured.
لقد تم شفاء السم الخاص بي.
It's time to show the officials
حان الوقت لإظهار المسؤولين
who truly rules this empire.
من يحكم هذه الإمبراطورية حقا؟
Today,
اليوم،
attend court with me.
حضر المحكمة معي.
Have you heard?
هل سمعت؟
Her Grace left a divorce letter
تركت صاحبة السمو رسالة طلاق
and left.
وغادر.
Her Grace should exemplify virtue.
ينبغي لسماحتها أن تكون مثالاً للفضيلة.
Such behavior
مثل هذا السلوك
is childish.
إنه طفولي.
She disregards national dignity.
إنها تتجاهل الكرامة الوطنية.
Enough.
كافٍ.
I'm wondering who's spreading rumors here.
أنا أتساءل من الذي ينشر الشائعات هنا.
Turns out it is General Yan.
اتضح أنه الجنرال يان.
General Meng, you bring a sword to court.
الجنرال منغ، أحضر سيفًا إلى المحكمة.
Isn't that inappropriate?
أليس هذا غير مناسب؟
Do you know this Bloodthirsty Sword
هل تعرف هذا السيف المتعطش للدماء؟
was captured from bandits at Biancheng?
تم الاستيلاء عليها من قطاع الطرق في بيانتشنغ؟
It claimed countless lives,
لقد أودى بحياة عدد لا يحصى من الناس،
sealing throats with one cut.
ختم الحناجر بقطعة واحدة.
Had I not risked rescuing you,
لو لم أخاطر بإنقاذك،
would you be here waving swords?
هل ستكون هنا تلوح بالسيف؟
You...
أنت...
I'll show you my power!
سأريك قوتي!
As expected of General Meng,
كما هو متوقع من الجنرال منغ،
great skills!
مهارات عظيمة!
- Impressive! - Impressive skills and strength!
- مثير للإعجاب! - مهارات وقوة مثيرة للإعجاب!
What nonsense.
ما هذا الهراء.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
Where are the loyal officials?
أين المسئولين المخلصين؟
All are the Prince Regent's lackeys.
كلهم أتباع الأمير الوصي.
Be patient.
كن صبوراً.
We'll see the result soon.
سوف نرى النتيجة قريبا.
The Prince Regent has arrived.
لقد وصل الأمير الوصي.
The Prince Regent is here. Hurry!
الأمير الوصي هنا. أسرع!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحياتي جلالتك.
Let's begin.
لنبدأ.
What matters do my esteemed officials have to report?
ما هي الأمور التي يتوجب على مسئولي الكرام الإبلاغ عنها؟
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
the southwestern frontier's conflict has been quelled.
تم إخماد الصراع على الحدود الجنوبية الغربية .
The Prince Regent sent General Meng to lead the troops.
أرسل الأمير الوصي الجنرال منغ لقيادة القوات.
He fought for three days and nights without rest.
لقد قاتل لمدة ثلاثة أيام وليالي دون راحة.
Both the Prince Regent and General Meng have rendered great service.
لقد قدم كل من الأمير الوصي والجنرال منغ خدمات عظيمة.
Assisting Your Majesty in governing the realm
مساعدة جلالتك في حكم المملكة
is my sacred duty.
هذا واجبي المقدس.
General Meng merits praise for his command. He deserves rewards.
يستحق الجنرال منغ الثناء على قيادته، ويستحق المكافأة.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكرا لك جلالتك.
However,
لكن،
I have heard
لقد سمعت
General Meng was besieged by bandits.
كان الجنرال منغ محاصرًا من قبل قطاع الطرق.
In that critical moment,
في تلك اللحظة الحرجة،
General Yan led reinforcements,
قاد الجنرال يان التعزيزات،
so you broke the siege.
لقد كسرت الحصار.
General Yan also contributed. He deserves rewards too.
ساهم الجنرال يان أيضًا، وهو يستحق المكافأة أيضًا.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
this was merely my duty.
لقد كان هذا مجرد واجبي.
I seek no rewards.
لا أسعى للحصول على أي مكافآت.
General Yan's toils merit high praise.
تستحق جهود الجنرال يان الثناء الكبير.
Yet he declines rewards.
ومع ذلك فهو يرفض المكافآت.
It's truly commendable.
إنه أمر جدير بالثناء حقا.
In my view,
في رأيي،
the disaster relief funds allocation
تخصيص أموال الإغاثة من الكوارث
should also be entrusted to General Yan.
وينبغي أن يعهد بهذا الأمر إلى الجنرال يان أيضًا.
My esteemed officials,
مسئولي الكرام،
what do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
- Your Majesty is wise.
- جلالتك حكيم.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
regarding the disaster relief funds,
فيما يتعلق بأموال الإغاثة من الكوارث،
another official has already handled this.
لقد تعامل مسؤول آخر مع هذا الأمر بالفعل.
Lord Father,
يا رب الأب،
didn't you instruct me
ألم تأمرني
to reward and punish justly?
المكافأة والعقاب بعدل؟
Reward them. They deserve it.
كافئهم، فهم يستحقون ذلك.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
Lord Father,
يا رب الأب،
does the sword I bestowed upon you
هل السيف الذي منحته لك
serve well?
هل تخدم جيدا؟
Your Majesty's gifted sword
سيف جلالتك الموهوب
cuts iron like clay and shatters all defenses.
يقطع الحديد مثل الطين ويحطم كل الدفاعات.
By Your Majesty's grace,
بفضل جلالتكم،
I became the first one in our dynasty
لقد أصبحت الأول في سلالتنا
to bear a sword in court.
حمل السيف في المحكمة.
As long as it serves.
طالما أنه يخدم.
However,
لكن،
in the court,
في المحكمة،
why does another sword appear?
لماذا يظهر سيف آخر؟
General Meng,
الجنرال منغ،
I don't remember it clearly.
لا أتذكر ذلك بوضوح.
Did I bestow
هل منحت
this sword upon you?
هذا السيف عليك؟
Well...
حسنًا...
General Meng,
الجنرال منغ،
since this sword wasn't bestowed by me,
بما أن هذا السيف لم يمنحه لي،
and now you bear a sword in court,
والآن تحمل سيفًا في المحكمة،
what punishment do you deserve?
ما هو العقاب الذي تستحقه؟
By our dynastic law,
بموجب قانوننا الأسري،
bearing swords in court
حمل السيوف في المحكمة
is deemed regicide.
يعتبر قتلا للملك.
You villain,
أيها الشرير
kicking me when I'm down.
يركلني عندما أكون في الأسفل.
Who's the villain? Who's malicious?
من الشرير؟ من الخبيث؟
Loyal officials know it best.
إن المسؤولين الموالين يعرفون ذلك على أفضل وجه.
Shi Yu,
شي يو,
don't test my patience!
لا تختبر صبري!
You sit in that position
أنت تجلس في هذا الوضع
solely by the Prince Regent's favor.
بفضل فضل الأمير الوصي فقط.
So by your logic,
لذا، وفقًا لمنطقك،
does the empire
هل الإمبراطورية
bear the Gao name?
تحمل اسم غاو؟
- Calm down, Your Majesty.
- اهدأ يا جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
I failed to discipline my subordinate.
لقد فشلت في تأديب مرؤوسي.
I shall return
سوف أعود
this sword to you.
هذا السيف لك.
Lord Father,
يا رب الأب،
why must you do this?
لماذا يجب عليك أن تفعل هذا؟
If you don't like
إذا كنت لا تحب
the sword I gifted you, then...
السيف الذي أهديته لك، إذن...
General Yan,
الجنرال يان
you shall receive it.
سوف تتلقاها.
Thanks, Your Majesty.
شكرا جلالتك.
Remember this.
تذكر هذا.
This sword
هذا السيف
strikes down corrupt officials
يضرب المسؤولين الفاسدين
and crushes despotic gentry as well.
ويسحق النبلاء المستبدين أيضًا.
No prior approval is needed.
لا حاجة لموافقة مسبقة.
I am deeply grateful.
أنا ممتن للغاية.
I'll wield it wisely.
سأستخدمه بحكمة.
As for the disaster relief funds,
أما بالنسبة لأموال الإغاثة من الكوارث،
I've entrusted them to you.
لقد أوكلتهم إليك.
Do not disappoint me.
لا تخيب ظني.
I shall fulfill your trust without fail,
سأفي بثقتك دون فشل،
even at the cost of my life.
حتى لو كان ذلك على حساب حياتي.
If there's nothing else to report,
إذا لم يكن هناك شيء آخر للإبلاغ عنه،
then
ثم
the court is dismissed.
تم رفض المحكمة.
- Farewell, Your Majesty.
- وداعا جلالتك.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
♪Without fate, this dream would fade♪
♪بدون القدر، هذا الحلم سوف يتلاشى♪
♪Without you, my life would quietly end♪
♪بدونك، حياتي ستنتهي بهدوء♪
♪Fade like drifting clouds♪
♪تتلاشى مثل السحب المنجرفة♪
♪Half dream, half illusion♪
♪نصف حلم، ونصف وهم♪
♪Fated or fleeting♪
♪مقدر أو عابر♪
♪Spring breeze falls from my brow♪
♪نسائم الربيع تهب من جبهتي♪
♪Where to go, I do not know♪
♪أين أذهب، لا أعرف♪
♪I turn, and all is gone♪
♪أتحول، وكل شيء قد ذهب♪
♪Ask how deep the dust of love runs♪
♪اسأل عن مدى عمق غبار الحب♪
♪How strong longing grows♪
♪ما أشد الشوق الذي ينمو♪
♪I play till the final note♪
♪ألعب حتى النغمة الأخيرة♪
♪Let fate cut like a blade♪
♪دع القدر يقطع مثل الشفرة♪
♪I bid you one last farewell♪
♪أقول لك وداعا أخيرا♪
♪I know not love's emptiness nor hatred's pain♪
♪لا أعرف فراغ الحب ولا ألم الكراهية♪
♪When we meet again, the snow will melt away♪
♪عندما نلتقي مرة أخرى، سوف يذوب الثلج♪
♪One vow, so deep in love♪
♪عهد واحد، عميق في الحب♪
♪I'd give my life for it♪
♪سأعطي حياتي من أجله♪